smokoo.co.za 2011-12-12

# 

  * **Smokoo Privacy Policy**

**Preamble**

It is the role of the Smokoo.com website (hereinafter referred to as “the site” or “we” or “the company”) to provide an online platform for the sale by auction of saleable products and services through the use of proprietary pay-to-bid software. 

In order to participate in the auctions you must register, purchase bids, place them and, when making a successful bid, to pay the item price. Each of these actions requires the collection, storage and use of selected personal and financial data by the site. 

The following Privacy Policy explains how the company protects and utilises such data and, in accepting its content along with the Terms and Conditions, you provide your express consent to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal data as detailed below.

**Data Collection**

As a casual visitor to The Site, it is not necessary to provide any personal data and most pages are accessible without doing so. During these visits we may collect basic information about your computer and connection such as its IP address, what browser you are using and your operating system, your country of origin as well as which pages you visit. This is fairly standard practice on most websites and is performed using tiny file called “cookies’ that are stored on your computer and can be retrieved as required.

  When registering as an active bidder we need to collect and store rather more information which is as follows:

  * email address, physical contact details including residential address, telephone numbers and date of birth;
  * information regarding all transactions performed on The Site;
  * shipping and billing information;
  * Financial information such as credit card details, Paypal account etc.

**Data Uses**

Most information we collect is intended to make your experience on the site simple, safe and efficient. To these ends you agree that we may use your personal information to :

  * provide the services and client support that you request;
  * resolve any disputes, manage accounts and troubleshoot any problems;
  * enforce the terms and conditions and prevent any prohibited or illegal activities on the site;
  * measure, improve and customize all aspects of the site and its services;
  * Optionally, keep you informed regarding updates, special offers and promotional activities from which you may benefit.

**Disclosure of Data**

In accordance with applicable laws, we may disclose personal information if required by law to do so in order to enforce our policies or respond to claims of violation of rights or in order to protect the rights, property or safety of others.

We may also share personal data, as necessary, with third party contractors such as wholesalers and courier companies that operate in support of The Site and its services. 

Where there is reason to suspect fraud or other illegal practice we may also disclose personal details to investigators, debt collection services, law enforcement agencies or other government officials, but only upon presentation of a subpoena, court order or equivalent legal documentation.

With the exception of the above contingencies we will not share your personal information with any other third party for any purpose whatever.

**Displayed Information**

During the registration process you will be asked to select a User Name. This acts as an alias enabling you to keep your true identity private unless you choose, voluntarily, to disclose it. Note that, when accessing the site from a shared computer, your user name may remain visible to other users.

**Maintaining Your Personal Data**

When logged in to the site, you may access your account details and make basic changes as required. You are advised to update these details promptly when such changes occur or if you find any existing details to be incorrect.

**Cancellation of Accounts**

You have the right to close your Smokoo user account at any time by making use of the form provided. Upon cancellation, in order to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect outstanding debts, settle disputes, assist investigations, troubleshoot problems, enforce our terms and conditions or take any other action permitted under law, we may retain certain information from closed accounts. All such data, however, is removed from all public access via the site. Allow up to three days for the complete removal of your information from all of our records.

**Use of Cookies**

As explained earlier, these are used to collect data about how you access the site and your preferences and are used solely to improve the user experience. You are free to switch of this facility in your browser if you prefer. It will not affect your ability to bid in auctions but could limit some secondary functions.

**Security Measures  
**  
All of your personal data is password protected. Your password is private and personal and no Smokoo employee will ever ask you by email or any other medium to reveal it. Should you ever receive such a request you are advised NOT TO COMPLY and to report the incident to Smokoo IMMEDIATELY.

Always remember to log out of your account after you have accessed it especially when accessing it from a public or shared computer as others could access your data. Smokoo can accept no responsibility for the consequences of ant failure on your part to keep you login credentials concealed.

We regard your data as a valuable asset and employ numerous security procedures to protect it. Our security measures include firewalls, high-level encryption and protection from viruses, spyware and other malware.

**Anti Spam Policy**

We will never use your email address without your express consent and neither will we rent our sell your email address to any third party. We employ special measures to prevent your email address being recorded by “spiders” or “web-crawlers” in an attempt to ensure that you are protected from “spamming”.

**Amendments to Privacy Policy  
**  
The Site reserves the right to amend or extend this policy document as may be indicated at any time. Any such changes will take full effect 10 days after their publication to the site.
